<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Ealen's Blog</title><link>https://ealen.fr/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Ealen's Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 20:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ealen.fr/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Nextcloud: The Ultimate Solution to Replace Google Drive and Others</title><link>https://ealen.fr/posts/raspberry/nextcloud/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ealen.fr/posts/raspberry/nextcloud/</guid><description>In today&amp;rsquo;s digital age, the need for secure storage solutions has never been greater.
Many of us have turned to giants like Google Drive or Microsoft OneDrive for their convenience and accessibility. However, have you ever wondered if there&amp;rsquo;s a better way to manage your personal data without compromising your privacy and flexibility?
In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore why Nextcloud stands as the ideal alternative to replace any drive provider.</description></item><item><title>DNS sinkhole, between Privacy and AdBlocker, configuration and feedback</title><link>https://ealen.fr/posts/raspberry/dns-sinkhole/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://ealen.fr/posts/raspberry/dns-sinkhole/</guid><description>DNS sinkhole technology provides an effective shield against unwanted online content without the hassle of installing client-side software. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how DNS sinkholes work, their advantages, and two leading solutions: Pi-Hole and AdGuard.
Introduction Filtering Filtering DNS queries plays a role in bolstering online security and safeguarding our digital privacy.
By intercepting and scrutinizing DNS requests, we can proactively block potential threats and security menaces before they even reach our devices.</description></item></channel></rss>